What kind of sparks can lobster and QWen3.5 create together?
We know that QWen3.5 was officially launched on New Year's Eve
It is also hailed as the most powerful open-source model.
Its capabilities can be said to rival GPT-4
kick Glaude 4.5's ass
can rival these top-tier international large models
compete with
Alright, so such a domestically produced, heavyweight Taiyuan large model
Can we invoke it for free in Ollama?
The answer is yes.
Next, a video
take you step by step to integrate QWen3.5 in Ollama from start to finish
complete the free invocation
Alright, without further ado
Let's get straight to the video.
The steps to connect are actually quite few.
It only takes four steps in total to get it done.
First of all,
If you don't have Ollama installed locally
You first need to download an Ollama
Make sure to download the latest version.
if your Ollama hasn't been updated for a long time
then do the same
First, update to the latest version
Well, there's not much to say about this
you just need to download it
Just proceed with the next steps to complete the installation.
After the installation is complete
Next, we'll install your QWen3.5 model on my Ollama.
your QWen3.5 model is ready
Then in the CMD, you'll see the command prompt
Right-click and run as administrator
Now, simply enter the command.
This is the open-source QWen3.5 model.
Okay, then press enter now
We just need to wait for Ollama to install QWen.
Soon we'll be able to see, hey
My OWen3.5 has already been installed locally.
At this point, I know some students might say
Brother Lei,
My local computer configuration isn't particularly high-end
Can QWen3.5 be deployed?
This is actually possible, why you ask?
this QWen3.5 model in Ollama
As you can see
followed by who
cloud is a new cloud-based model launched by Ollama
These new models
OK everyone can see they all have the cloud label
like Qwen3.5
Zhipu's 5
and Mini Max's 2.5
are all cloud-based
So what does this 'cloud' mean?
Ah, it means Ollama remotely helps you
has already deployed the full-powered versions of these models
you just need the Ollama client
you can quickly connect to the open-source model that Ollama has deployed for you
At this point, you don't need to worry about your computer's performance
because this full-powered large model
It is essentially not deployed locally on your device.
but is deployed on Ollama's servers
If you have Ollama, you can use it directly.
So this is the logic behind it.
So it doesn't matter if your computer isn't powerful enough
can be used
Okay, great. We've got it deployed quickly.
After the deployment is complete
Now, the third step is
we will log in to my Ollama account
Enter this command
press Enter and then after pressing Enter
It will automatically open the page
This is Ollama's login page
If it does not appear
Have you seen this address?
Manually paste it into your browser and you're good to go.
Alright then, now go ahead and fill in your OLED account
Some people say hey
Brother Lei, what should I do if I don't have an Ollama account?
What if you don't have an email address?
then we click the register button at the bottom
Then click Finish, and then next
in the input box above
Please fill in your email information
I will fill in my email information
Click Continue
At this point, it asks you to create and enter a password
Then you enter the password
Then click continue
Then click Next, okay
click Finish
Then, you'll need to log in to your email to receive the verification code.
The verification code has been sent to your email.
After entering the email,
It requires binding a phone number.
At this point, we will proceed to fill in our phone number.
Then click 'Send Verification Code', okay
After receiving the verification code on your phone
enter it
After entering the verification code
We have successfully logged in now.
Do you see it
I'm logged in now
After logging in, OK
Click on the connection below, OK
it shows that the login was successful
Now, the second step is already completed.
After completing this step,
Now we can proceed to the final step.
Use this command to start your OpenClaw
you can complete OpenClaw
connect to the QWen3.5 model in Ollama
Alright, now for the final step,
Use this command to initiate the interaction.
Alright, now let's try to start it up
return to the command window
Enter this command and hit enter.
Press Enter
After waiting for a moment,
As we can see
Our OpenClaw has started
and the model being used is Ollama's QWen3.5 cloud model
But can it be used?
Next, we can open the command window
or open our Feishu to test it
Well, I'll just open my command window here.
After that,
Alright, let's go ahead and open a new session for it.
Open a new window
Then let's ask it
I've switched to a new large model for you
Tell me which large model you are using.
Let's just give it this one line of command
Then click send
Alright, let's take a look at what model it returns for us.
See it?
It says what I'm using now is
the Qwen3.5 model
In that case, let's use OpenClaw
You can freely use the QWen3.5 model in Ollama.
the QWen3.5 model
Okay, someone might ask at this point
Is it really that simple?
Can I use Ollama's cloud model for free like this?
Are there any restrictions?
The answer is yes.
for example, Ollama's cloud-based model
they also have costs, right
So then the usage of Ollama
There are also usage limits for cloud model calls.
So where exactly is this quota limit?
Let me show you
For this, click on the account in the upper right corner
After clicking,
Take a look here, everyone
This is the usage limit for the cloud model.
It is based on a percentage
There is a certain weekly quota
and there's a certain quota every four hours
So when you've used up this quota
then the cloud model cannot be invoked
So I just asked two questions
So basically, it consumes about 1.2%
So this free model
It should be possible to make around 100 calls every four hours.
based on the context of your talking
Its billing method is different.
So overall
this free quota
compared to other free quotas
Ollama is indeed more substantial
So now, we've completed the integration in OpenClaw
to integrate the QWen3.5 feature
I'm Brother Lei
share a useful tip every day